A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Pamphlet File, Series 1 FA006
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation records, Pamphlet File, Series 1
1902-1986
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation
FA006
4.4 Cubic Feet 9 document boxes and 1 oversized flat box.
Scope and Contents
The Rockefeller Foundation maintained a vast collection of published pamphlets, academic papers, book manuscripts and program reports and summaries, or other booklets that reference the Foundation or members of the Rockefeller family or were created by RF leaders, employees, or grantees.
Arrangement
Alphabetical by subject.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
- Disease: Diphtheria: International, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Disease: Diphtheria: United States, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Disease: Flies: International, 1913-1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  General
  Brazil, China, Honduras, Mexico
- Disease: Flies: United States, 1913-1921 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Alabama, Connecticut, Idaho, Indiana, Kansas, Michigan, Louisiana, Mississippi, New York, North Carolina, South Carolina, Tennessee, Texas, Utah, Wisconsin and General Information
- Disease: Hookworm: International, 1920-1926 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Australia
- Disease: Hookworm: International, 1909-1917 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  British Guiana, British West Indies, Canada
- Disease: Hookworm: International, 1905-1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Colombia, Ceylon, Grenada
- Disease: Hookworm: International, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Honduras, Indochina, Jamaica, London, Mauritius,, Persia
- Disease: Hookworm: United States, 1911-1928 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  General Information, Surveys, Flyers
- Disease: Hookworm: United States, 1912-1923 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Alabama
- Disease: Hookworm: United States, 1914-1924 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Arkansas
- Disease: Hookworm: United States, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Florida, Georgia
- Disease: Hookworm: United States, 1912-1914 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Kentucky, Louisiana
- Disease: Hookworm: United States, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Mississippi, North Carolina
- Disease: Hookworm: United States, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Tennessee, Texas, Virginia
- Disease: Leprosy: International, 1920-1933 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  British Empire, Calcutta, Cochin, Korea, Madagascar, Mexico, Philippines
- Disease: Miscellaneous: Measles, Whooping Cough, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Disease: Leprosy: United States: General Information, 1913-1916 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Disease: Malaria: International: General, 1915-1963 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Disease: Malaria: International, 1915-1940 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Algeria, Belgium, Brazil, British Malaya, Bolivia, Costa Rica, Ceylon, Germany, India, Israel, Italy, Netherlands, Mauritius, Philippines, Salvador
- Disease: Malaria: United States: General, 1920-1958 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Disease: Malaria: United States, 1916-1927 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Arkansas, California, Georgia, Mississippi, South Carolina, Texas
- Disease: Poliomyelitis: United States, 1911-1932 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Disease: Tuberculosis: International, 1915-1932 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Brazil, Colombia, Costa Rica, Czechoslovakia, England, France, Italy, Spain
- Disease: Tuberculosis: United States, 1911-1936 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Disease: Venereal: International, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Disease: Venereal: United States, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Disease: Vermin (Rats): International, 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Disease: Vermin (Rats): United States, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Disease: Yellow Fever: International, 1915-1931 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  Brazil, Colombia, Ecuador, Guatemala, Honduras, Mexico, Salvador
- Disease: Yellow Fever: United States, 1920-1942 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Education: Colleges and Universities: United States: Graduate Work, 1937-1940 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Economics: "France and the Economic Conference", 1933 June (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Education: American Youth Commission, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Education: Astronomy: Mt. Palomar, 1933-1948 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Education: Colleges and Universities: International, 1919-1972 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  China, Costa Rica, Egypt, England, Hawaii, Korea, Norway
- Education: Colleges and Universities: United States, 1926-1957 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Education: General Education Board, 1917-1962 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  Charter, By-Laws, Funding, Miscellaneous
- Education: Graduate Record Exams, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Education: Language, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Education: Policy and Administration, 1936-1950 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Education: Political, 1938-1941 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Education: Post War, 1933-1934 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Education: Reports: New York, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Education: Rural, 1920-1939 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Education: Secondary, 1935-1950 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Education: Southern States, 1908-1947 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Education: Statistic Tests and Measurements, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Education: Wartime, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Educational Assistance to Developing Areas, 1930-1966 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Floods, 1927-1928 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- General Education Board, 1902-1964 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- International Health Board, 1914-1926 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- International Rice Research Institute, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 54)
- International Sanitation Commission, 1915-1928 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  Campaign Literature and Posters
- League of Nations, 1922-1931 (Box 4, Folder 56)
- Library of Congress: Miscellaneous Informational Pamphlets, 1958-1969 (Box 4, Folder 57)
- Library of Congress: National Union Catalog of Manuscript Collections, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 58)
- Library Science, 1931-1972 (Box 4, Folder 59)
- Massachusetts' Lobster Hatchery and Research Station, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 60)
- Medicine: Hospitals: International, 1924-1932 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  Australia, Brazil, China, Japan
- Medicine: Hospitals: United States, 1920-1930 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  California, Connecticut, Louisiana, Missouri, New York, Oregon
- Medicine: Infant Mortality, 1909-1921 (Box 4, Folder 63)
- XXVIII International Congress for History of Medicine; Actes Proceedings Vol. l; Paris, 1982 August-September (Box 4, Folder 64)
- Medicine: Mental Health, 1913-1931 (Box 4, Folder 65)
- Medicine: Study, Teaching, Practice, Reports: International, 1915-1941 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  Australia, Canada, Eastern Europe, Europe, Far East, Great Britain, Pacific Islands, South America
- Medicine: Nursing: United States, 1919-1932 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  General, Illinois, Minnesota, New York, Ohio, Pennsylvania, Virginia
- Medicine: Nursing: International, 1920-1932 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  Brazil, China, Jamaica, Rio de Janeiro, Switzerland
- Medicine: Study, Teaching, Practice, Reports: United States, 1927-1947 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  Connecticut, Georgia, Illinois, Iowa, Maryland, Mississippi, New York, Ohio, Pennsylvania
- Missions, 1907-1927 (Box 5, Folder 70)
- Motion Pictures, 1919-1936 (Box 5, Folder 71)
- National Research Council, 1919-1939 (Box 5, Folder 72)
- Oral History, 1965-1975 (Box 5, Folder 73)
- Philanthropic Legislation: RF Response, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 74)
- Philanthropy: American Fund for Public Service, 1923-1930 (Box 5, Folder 75)
- Philanthropy: General, 1915-1963 (Box 5, Folder 76)
- Philanthropy: John Simon Guggenheim, 1925-1932 (Box 5, Folder 77)
- Philanthropy: Phelps-Stokes Fund, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 78)
- Population Control, 1938-1979 (Box 6, Folder 79)
- Population: Birth Registration, 1915-1920 (Box 6, Folder 80)
- Public Administration, 1943-1947 (Box 6, Folder 81)
- Public Health: Centers: United States, 1921-1926 (Box 6, Folder 82)
- Public Health: Dental Care, 1918-1937 (Box 6, Folder 83)
- Public Health: Education: International: China, undated (Box 6, Folder 84)
- Public Health: Education: United States: Alabama, 1914-1932 (Box 6, Folder 85)
- Public Health: Education: United States: North Carolina, 1914-1932 (Box 6, Folder 86)
- Public Health: Food, Water, Milk, 1911-1932 (Box 6, Folder 87)
- Public Health: Health Department (States) Publications, 1921-1931 (Box 6, Folder 88)
- Public Health: Inventions, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 89)
- Public Health: Life Insurance Publications, undated (Box 6, Folder 90)
- Public Health: Pamphlets and Reports: International, 1914-1931 (Box 6, Folder 91)
  Brazil, British Honduras, Canada, England and Wales, France, Germany
- Public Health: Pamphlets and Reports: International, 1926-1941 (Box 7, Folder 92)
  India, Ireland, Italy, Netherlands
- Public Health: Pamphlets and Reports: International, 1921-1934 (Box 7, Folder 93)
  Honduras, Mexico, Philippines, Puerto Rico, South Africa, Yugoslavia
- Public Health: Pamphlets and Reports: United States, 1914-1931 (Box 7, Folder 94)
- Public Health: Pamphlets and Reports: United States, 1932-1946 (Box 7, Folder 95)
- Public Health: Reports: International: The Tropics, 1924-1939 (Box 7, Folder 96)
- Public Health: Privies: International, 1914-1922 (Box 7, Folder 97)
  Colombia, Costa Rica, Mauritius, Panama, Philippines, Trinidad
- Public Health: Privies: United States, 1913-1930 (Box 7, Folder 98)
  Alabama, Delaware, Georgia, Kentucky, Mississippi, North Carolina, Ohio, Texas
- Public Health: Rockefeller Sanitary Commission, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 99)
- Public Health: Sewage Disposal, 1913-1931 (Box 8, Folder 100)
- Public Health: Sex Education, 1914-1933 (Box 8, Folder 101)
- Public Health: United States Public Health Service, 1915-1929 (Box 8, Folder 102)
- Rockefeller Foundation: Addresses, 1963-1967 (Box 8, Folder 103)
- Rockefeller Foundation: Annual Reports, 1922-1938 (Box 8, Folder 104)
- Rockefeller Foundation: Charter, Purpose and Program, 1927-1969 (Box 8, Folder 105)
- Rockefeller Foundation: International Health Division (IHD): Memorandum for Staff Members, 1934, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 105A)
- Rockefeller Foundation: Clippings, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 106)
- Rockefeller Foundation: Correspondence (Published), 1923 (Box 8, Folder 107)
- Rockefeller Foundation: Directories, 1951-1967 (Box 8, Folder 108)
- Rockefeller Foundation: History, 1914-1963 (Box 8, Folder 109)
- Rockefeller Foundation: Information for Fellows and Scholars, 1938, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 110)
- Rockefeller Foundation: Manual for Overseas Staff, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 111)
- Rockefeller Foundation: Staff Members Manual, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 111A)
- Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, 1914-1922 (Box 8, Folder 112)
- Rockefeller Homes: Kykuit, Basset Hall, 1976-1984 (Box 8, Folder 113)
- Rockefeller State Park Preserve (Dedication), 1986 (Box 8, Folder 114)
- Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 115)
- Russell Sage Foundation, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 116)
- Sleepy Hollow: Tales of the Old Dutch Graveyard, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 117)
- Tennessee Valley Authority, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 118)
- Unemployment, 1930, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 119)
- Uniform Offense Classification for Criminal Statistics, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 120)
- White House Conference on Children in a Democracy, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 121)
- World's Fair - New York, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 122)
- World War I (Miscellaneous), 1917-1931 (Box 9, Folder 123)
- World War II: Asia, 1938-1941 (Box 9, Folder 124)
- World War II: Latin America, 1940-1941 (Box 9, Folder 125)
- World War II: Soviet Union, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 126)
- World War II: War Work, 1939-1943 (Box 9, Folder 127)
- Oversize Material (Box 10)
  - "Aviso relativo ao Perico das Moscas", undated
    Separated Materials
    From Box 1, Folder 3
  - "Hookworm Disease, Its Prevention and Cure", 1918
    From Box 1, Folder 7
  - Mauritius Medical and Health Department, Better Health Campaign, "Ankylostomiasis Causes Bad Health", undated
    From Box 1, Folder 8
  - "Germ of Laziness Found?" - article from "The Sun", 1902 December 5
    From Box 1, Folder 9
  - Scientific American Supplement, 1915 March 13
  - "Para los dengosos" - article from "El Oriente", 1932 April 12
    From Box 1, Folder 20
  - "Rockefeller Foundation Provides Yellow Fever Vaccine Free to Government for American Armed Forces", 1942 March 19
    From Box 2, Folder 31
  - "On the Trail of the Yellow Fever Germ", 1920 April 1
  - "War Time Economies", undated
    From Box 4, Folder 62
  - "Rockefeller Foundation Urges More Trained Personnel in Medical Sciences", 1947 March 21
    From Box 5, Folder 69
  - Press Release from Rockefeller Foundation re cooperation with National Research Council, 1919 March 31
    From Box 5, Folder 72
  - "Benevolent Foundations and Efficient Philanthropy", John D. Rockefeller, "The Saturday Evening Post", 1915 April 10
    From Box 5, Folder 76
  - Rockefeller Center Article with Photos, "L'Illustration", 1932 August 13
  - "The Baldwin Times", Bay Minette, Alabama, 1922 June 1
    From Box 6, Folder 85
  - Information from the Department of the Provincial Secretary, Public Health Service, Canada, undated
    From Box 6, Folder 91
  - "Schema van de Organisatie van de Medisch-Hygienische Propaganda - van den Dienst der Volksgezondheid", undated
  - "Hookworm Disease in Bengal" and "Sanitary Reform", Articles in "The Englishman", India, 1918 November 29
    From Box 7, Folder 92
  - "Government Experts to Test Miles Process to Recover Sewage Grease", Article from "Oil Paint and Drug Reporter", undated
    From Box 7, Folder 94
  - "Yale News", Institute of Human Relations Dedication Issue, 1931 May 9
  - Poster Illustrating Construction of a Sanitary Privy, Panana, 1921
    From Box 7, Folder 97
  - "Decreto Numero 30 de 1919", Republic of Panama (2 copies), 1919 September 12
  - "Instrucciones para la construccion de excusados", Colombia, undated
  - "Decreto Numero 17 de 1922", Republic of Panama, 1922 May 17
  - "Decreto Numero 33 de 1922", Republic of Panama, 1922 December 15
  - Mounted Cartoon Depicting Diseases Resulting from Insanitary Privies, Mississippi, undated
    From Box 7, Folder 98
  - "Giving Away Money", Chester T. Crowell, "The Saturday Evening Post", 1926 May 15
    From Box 8, Folder 109
  - "Education...an Investment in People", Committee on Education, United States Chamber of Commerce, 1944 November